COVER LETTER

am writing to express my interest in the **REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER** position that you have posted. I believe that my experience and skills make me a strong candidate for this position.

I have been developing software for over 9+ years, with a focus on mobile development for the last 7+ years. My experience includes developing native applications for iOS and Android as well as cross-platform applications using React Native and flutter. I have also developed web apps using React js and other React js libraries.

My core strengths include being able to quickly learn new technologies, being able to work independently or as part of a team, and being able to communicate effectively with both technical and non-technical people. I am also skilled at troubleshooting bugs and finding solutions to difficult problems.

I would like to thank you for your consideration and look forward to hearing from you soon.



Hanafi Taofiq

REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER

Dynamic and innovative professional with 7+ years of invaluable hands-on experience in handling several simulteneous creative design projects, concept creation, graphics design, web design and mobile app development with react native. Equipped with the ability to escalate brand awareness by utilizing skills gained in the creative industry, being able to identify opportunities, overcome objections, build long-term mutually beneficial relationships with vendors, workforce and clients. establishing a successful and lucrative company

JAVASCRIPT	100%	NODE JS	100%	FIREBASE	100%
CSS 3	100%	MATERIAL UI	100%	NATIVE BASE	100%
HTML 5	100%	REACT JS	100%	MYSQL	100%
SKILLS	. i 9			ARABIC	50%
HTML & CSS TEMPLATE MONSTER online program			Nov., 2019	ENGLISH	80%
JAVA PROGRAMMING	o program		Mar., 2021	YORUBA	100%
GREAT LEARNING onlin			, 2021	LANGUAGES	
ANDROID APPLICATION DEVELOPER			Mar., 2021	RESEARCHING Mar., 2021	
NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORP(NYSC) Airforce Comprehensive School Uyo			2023	DEBUGGING,, DESIGNING,	
CERTIFICATIONS				HOOBIES SPORT, CODING,	
Iqra Nur/pri School Ilor		e	1000 - 1000		
Asa Local Gov't Sec. School Budo Tuntun PRIMARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE			2000 - 2006	MS WORD	100%
SENIOR SECONDARY S			2008 - 2013	PHOTOSHOP	95%
DIPLOMA IN ENGLISH College of Arabic and Kwara State			2013 - 2015	ANDROID STUDIO CORELDRAW	100%
B.Ed ISLAMIC STUDIES Ahmadu Bello University Zaria, Kaduna State			2016 - 2022	VS CODE	100%
EDUCATIONAL BA	CKGROUND			SOFTWARES/ID	E
08159832838,09032	339903 M	lale Ilorin, Kwara	State, Nigeria	1995 ayodejiokoh@gr	mail.com
MOBILE NO.	SE	X: PERMANENT	ADDRESS	D.O.B EMAIL	

100%

100%

MONGODB

RESTFUL API

RESPONSIBILITIES

Design and implement user interface components for JavaScript-based web and mobile applications.

Work as a part of a small team that includes other react native developers, designers, QA experts, and managers

Build app and UI components from prototypes and wireframes

Work with native modules as and when required

Use Native APIs for tight integrations with both platforms – Android and iOS

Write automated tests to ensure error-free code and performance

Improve front-end performance by eliminating performance bottlenecks

Create front-end modules with maximum code reusability and efficiency

Implement clean, smooth animations to provide an excellent user interface

Work with third-party dependencies and APIs

Work with Redux architecture to improve performance of the websites/mobile apps

Coordinate with the cross-functional teams to build apps in stipulated time/budget.

EXPERIENCE

INSTRUCTOR (REACT, REACT NATIVE)

 Taking web and mobile development courses at femtech Ilorin, Kwara State. Nigeria.

Tech Stack: HMTL, CSS, JS, NodeJs, tempelate engines(ejs, handlebars) React, React-native and other js libraries.

JS(REACT, REACT NATIVE) DEVELOPER (REMOTE)

- Responsible for implementing the web pages design by the UI/UX Designers.
- Implementing the front and backend of mobile app with React Native for both android and IOS.
- Building reuseable code for future use.

Tech Stack: React, Node MongoDB, GraphQL, TypeScript, React Native, Tailwindcss, Sass, Material UI.

GRAPHICS DESIGNER

2019 - 2020

Ajenifuja printing press, Ilorin Kwara State

GRAPHICS & MOTION DESIGNER

2016 - 2019

No 39 Benin Street, Sabon Gari Zaria, Kaduna State